Over here.
Where are you?
In the main cavern.
Watch your step!
Point your flashlights up here.
It's incredible.
Look at the wings.
- Did you hear that?
- Yeah.
Came from down here.
Check the ground. Do you see this?
Right there. Look at that.
Careful, careful.
It's tracks.
What is that? Did you find something?
Quinn! We found it!
We found the creature!
You were right all along.
They all thought you were crazy,
but you're gonna prove them wrong.
Timing couldn't be better.
The investors are getting impatient.
I knew you were more than a legend.
Don't shine your lights directly at it.
You're stressing him out.
It's okay. Nobody's gonna hurt you.
We just wanna get to know you, that's all.
Up there!
Hey! What was that?
Did you see it?
Where is it?
You okay?
Watch out!
Hey, he's getting away!
Come on! Let's go!
I got him in the wing! Let's get him!
He went that way!
Going towards the exit!
- Come on!
- Come on! Let's go!
You all right?
Which way?
There!
The target's
headed to the mountain.
- Let's go!
- Come on!
There you are!
Copy that. We're on it.
- We're on your tail.
- Come on! Come on! Come on!
I'm not letting you get away from me!
Son of a...
Come on!
Quinn!
- Follow me! It went this way.
- Okay.
Come on! Come on.
No signs.
It's gotta be somewhere.
Come on. We're on foot!
Move it! Move it! Let's go!
All right. Fan out! Fan out!
His wing is injured.
It couldn't have gotten far.
- Hey, look!
- Close.
- Go over here.
- Look at this. Look at that track.
He's right. Come on.
- On the lookout.
- Eyes open!
- Stay low! Stay low!
- I think it stopped.
Yeah, a branch.
- See that?
- Yep.
Yeah.
Come on! Down here!
This way!
It went to the side.
Cut it off.
In Kansas City,
5 stands for news.
And now a story has come out
of Latin America
that is spreading like a fever
across the world.
El Chupacabra, a strange animal
that feeds off the blood of goats
has the makings of a modern-day legend.
Farmers in the small Mexican town
of San Javier
are claiming to have seen it,
and dozens of goats in the community
have been mysteriously killed
without any explanation.
Skeptics are dismissing it
as some sort of hoax, arguing this story...
I dare you to talk to Becca.
Wanna bet? Let's go.
- Hey, Becca.
- Hey.
Wanna go to the movies this weekend?
Uh... No, thanks. Anyways, I just...
- You're not supposed to have this.
- I know, just give it back.
That game sucks.
Ew. What is that?
Picadillo.
Is that how you say "vomit" in Spanish?
It's just hamburger meat.
Whatever, taquito.
I told you not to call me that.
Or what?
You're gonna tell on me to your dad?
You're such a loser.
- So weird.
- I know, right?
What's that smell?
Hi, baby. Barbecue tacos.
Again? We had that last week.
I had some meat left in the freezer.
Why can't we just have normal food, huh?
This is normal food.
Hey, look at what
finally came this morning.
I'm not going.
What are you talking about?
We've been planning this trip for months.
And I've been telling you,
I don't wanna go.
Why not?
Talk to me.
Because I don't care about Mexico, okay?
I don't care about the music.
I don't care about the food.
I just don't wanna go.
What is it, Alejandro?
Did something happen at school?
Is that kid still giving you a hard time?
I just... I just had a bad day.
It's good you are going to Mexico.
Being with family will help you.
But I don't even remember them.
That's why your dad
wanted you to go on this trip.
He wanted you to know them better.
Can you at least come with me?
Mi amor, you know I can't.
I have work.
But it's only for spring break and
your abuelo will take good care of you.
Your dad always said
San Javier was a magical place.
And your cousins will be there.
Trust me. You're going to have fun.
You're not going to eat?
I told you, I hate barbacoa.
Are you sure you're not hungry?
I can make you a grilled cheese.
I'm okay.
I'm sorry for snapping at you.
I didn't mean to.
Don't worry.
I know it's been a hard year.
Your dad fought so hard
so he could go on this trip with you,
but cancer was a fight
he just couldn't win.
I know. I miss him.
I miss him too.
But listen to me, Alejandro.
You are not alone in this.
You've got your family,
and your family got your back.
You understand?
I love you so much, honey.
Me too.
Adiós.
Gracias.
Show me what you're made of.
What are you doing?
I'm Chava, your grandpa.
Just wanted to see
what you got,
but clearly I'm gonna have to
teach you some moves.
You've grown up.
Thank you, miss.
De nada.
How was the flight?
What?
- Ay, Dios mío.
- How was your flight?
Mijo, vente aquí en frente
pa que veas mejor.
What?
Want to ride in front
so you can see better?
Oh. Uh, I'm okay, thanks.
So you really don't speak Spanish, huh?
A little? Un poco.
"Un poco."
Your dad didn't teach you?
He tried, I just didn't see the point.
What? That's your heritage.
Something to be proud of.
No one speaks Spanish in Kansas City.
Well, even better. You'd be the only kid
speaking two languages. How cool is that?
I don't think that's a good thing.
You look just like him.
Who?
Mi Beto. Your dad.
I miss him too, mijo.
Very, very much.
Where are you going?
I got you!
Memo, leave that chicken
alone and come meet your cousin.
- I almost caught it, Grandpa.
- Memo, Alex.
He and his sister came from the city
to spend the week with you.
He doesn't speak English.
So this is your chance
to brush up your Spanish.
Show him his room.
Cowabunga!
Leonardo is my favorite.
Come, I'll show you your room.
Cousin, cousin, cousin! Look over here.
This is my sister's bedroom.
Don't even think about going in there
or else she'll kill you.
Come here, cousin. I'll show you my room.
Cowabunga!
I love my room.
It's the best, right?
Where am I supposed to go?
Are you serious?
♪ Ven y dime todas esas cosas ♪
♪ Invítame a sentarme junto a ti ♪
♪ Escucharé todos tus sueños ♪
♪ En mi oído ♪
What are you looking at?
I was...
I'm kidding.
You must be Alex, I'm Luna.
Come on, primo.
We're in Mexico.
Here we hug and kiss.
Surprise!
- What the...
- Cowabunga!
- He has him by the neck.
- Get off!
Feel the fury of Azul!
What?
Give up, you scoundrel!
What is he doing?
Lucha libre.
Lucha what?
You seriously
don't know Relámpago Azul?
Do you live under a rock?
He was the toughest fighter ever.
- What did he say?
- Just watch.
- You recognize him?
- Azul!
- It's Grandpa.
- Abuelo?
He was as famous as El Santo.
Isn't he so cool?
He fought against
the greatest wrestlers of his time
and didn't lose a single match.
- He was the strongest.
- Azul!
He was awesome.
He believed in justice
and always protected the people.
Look at that!
Here comes El Chakal.
The worst of the worst.
El Chakal
was abuelo's arch enemy.
He was a dirty fighter.
He used every trick he could
to try to defeat abuelo
but was never able to.
He was horrible.
He's the one that threw abuelo
out of the ring
and gave him that injury.
What injury?
He fractured his skull and was in a coma
for almost a month.
That's why he had to give up fighting.
- What?
- Why'd you turn it off?
We were about to watch you
defeat El Chakal.
El Chakal...
To hell with him, I don't like that guy.
I didn't know
you were a famous luchador.
That was a long time ago.
- You guys hungry?
- Sí.
What do you say we get some food?
Go ahead, Alex. Choose one.
Wait, we're not... Are we?
Yeah. That's how we do things around here.
Choose this one, it looks yummier.
Or wait. Are you
one of those vegetarians, like Luna?
No, I eat meat.
I've just never seen food... alive.
Don't listen to them.
They're just messing with you.
You should have seen your face!
Grandpa!
There's another sick goat.
- Is it sick?
- Something sucked its blood.
- What?
- El Chupacabras.
El Chupa-what?
El Chupacabras. You've never heard of it?
It's a vampire
that feeds on the blood of goats.
It's the scariest monster
to ever exist.
That's just nonsense.
Chupacabras doesn't exist.
It's a fairytale.
Of course it exists.
It was all over the news.
No, don't buy everything
you see on TV, Memo.
It's true, Grandpa!
It was seen in San Javier.
Last week's sighting
proves that I've been right all along.
These creatures do exist.
And it's not just one.
The cub is in the early stages
of development,
weighing approximately 30 to 50 pounds.
While the adult weighs
approximately 500 to 800 pounds,
bear-like with retractable claws.
Based on this feather, it would appear
that the myths and legends are true.
They can fly.
Son of a...
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Shoot.
Hey! Turn it off!
Hey! You gotta turn that chopper off!
- You sure have a lot of empty cages.
- What are you doing here?
One word, Quinn. Results. We want results.
Look at this. We almost had it.
I didn't fly all the way here
for a feather.
You promised us its blood.
You said it had healing powers
and that it would revolutionize medicine.
You also said we'd make a lot of money.
You will.
You just gotta give me more time.
They're out of patience, Quinn.
You have till the end of this week.
If you don't find it by then,
then you'll have to wrap all this up.
Just remember, the people that I work for
don't deal well with disappointment.
And trust me. You don't want to cross 'em.
Abuelo?
Abuelo! Help!
Alex? Alex?
What happened? Are you all right?
- Primo!
- El Chupacabras!
- What happened?
- What?
- I saw it.
- El Chupacabras?
It was right there. Look!
You see it?
- You screamed like that for these?
- Oh, so scary.
- It was bigger. I swear!
- I'm going back to bed.
I'll go with you in case
the boogeyman pops out.
That Alex gets scared easily, huh?
He screamed like a baby.
- Abuelo?
- Hmm.
- Abuelo? Are you okay?
Beto? Did you see it?
I'm not Beto. I'm Alex.
What? Let me see that.
- You're bleeding.
- It's all right.
No, no, no, let's go inside.
Let's wash that cut.
But, abuelo, I saw it.
What is it?
Sorry.
I had a nightmare.
Oh, cousin.
Hey, little fella. Where did he go?
Are you okay?
You didn't see it?
See what?
Nothing.
Do you like cohetes?
Fireworks? No, they're dangerous.
Only if they blow up in your hands.
Come. I'll show you.
Trust me, primo. Vamos.
You gotta hold it like this.
- Throw it!
- Not yet. Wait.
You have to hold it and then let go!
Now, you do it.
You'll be just fine.
- I'll lose a finger.
- You'll still have nine.
Vamos, primo. You gotta live a little.
Take some risks.
Why is your English so good?
I watch lots of movies.
And I'm obsessed with the Beastie Boys.
You know them?
Of course.
What? You think Mexicans
only listen to mariachi?
Uh, no. I just...
I'm just messing with you.
You don't have to
take everything so literal.
I'm sorry about your dad.
It's all right.
It must be hard.
My mom put up his picture after he died.
You look like him.
So... are you going to try it?
Hold it. I'll tell you when.
Ready?
Now!
Well done!
Luna! I can't find grandpa!
What's going on?
- Abuelo is missing.
- What do you mean "missing"?
He forgets things and wanders off.
Come on. We gotta go.
Hurry up. Let's go.
- What took you so long?
- I needed my mask.
Shouldn't we call your mom?
No, you can't tell her.
Why not?
Because she will make abuelo
move out of the ranch.
Are you sure you know how to drive?
No, not really.
Abuelo's been teaching me, but...
Oh, boy.
Azul!
Last week, when we were chasing
the creature, there was an accident.
Car hit the creature here
then skid off the road.
Any idea what happened
to the creature or the cub?
No. But... we did find this.
Good work.
You guys check for him in the market.
I'll find you guys later.
Shouldn't we stick together?
- Don't worry. Memo will take care of you.
- Vamos.
Follow me!
I'll show you my favorite stands.
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Coming through.
Can I have a bag?
Sí, mijo. Son diez pesos, eh.
Gracias.
Want some?
- What is it?
- Crickets.
Are these... crickets?
Muy buenos.
Those aren't "buenos," those are bugs.
I'm hungry.
Let's go get tacos.
Hey! What? Hey!
Shouldn't we be looking for abuelo?
It's El Chupacabras.
Chupacabras?
Yeah.
People say it's a monster.
But it's not that bad.
Thank you. Cousin! Come here!
You have to try this.
- What is it?
- Just try it.
Oh,
that's really good. Muy bueno.
Told you so.
What are you guys doing?
You were supposed to be
looking for abuelo.
But we were hungry.
Sorry. Did you find him?
He's not here.
You like sesos?
Yeah.
What's sesos?
Brains.
God, I hate abuelo's taste in music.
Put this.
What's this?
"Pachuco."
La Maldita. They're an awesome band.
♪ No sé cómo te atreves
A vestirse de esa forma y salir ♪
♪ Así ♪
♪ En mis tiempos todo era elegante
Sin greñudos y sin rock ♪
♪ Hey pa fuiste pachuco ♪
♪ También te regañaban ♪
♪ Hey pa bailabas mambo ♪
♪ Tienes que recordarlo ♪
- What's a pachuco?
- A type of Mexican living in the US.
Am I a pachuco?
I guess.
♪ No sé cómo te atreves
A vestirse de esa forma y salir ♪
♪ Así ♪
♪ En mis tiempos todas las mujeres
Eran serias, no había punk ♪
♪ Hey pa fuiste pachuco ♪
♪ También te regañaban ♪
♪ Hey pa bailabas mambo ♪
♪ Tienes que recordarlo ♪
Over there!
Grandpa! Where are you going?
Thank God we found you.
- Abuelo! Are you okay?
- Hey!
- What are you doing here?
- We've been looking for you.
We didn't know
where you went.
I was just... taking a walk.
What's up with the goat?
I bought it.
Why?
Because I needed a goat.
Aww, it's so cute! I'll call it Pepito.
Copy that.
Who are these people?
Hey! Watch where you're going!
Move on! Come on!
There's nothing to see.
Come on, keep going.
Good morning, officer.
How can I help you, gentlemen?
I'm looking for El Chupacabra.
Chupacabras?
- Is he serious?
- Yeah.
No, I haven't seen El Chupacabras.
But my wife has a "big foot."
You can take her instead.
- What's he saying?
- He doesn't think that chupacabras exist.
- Gringo loco.
- He thinks that you're...
- I got that one.
- Yeah, okay.
Why don't you ask him
if he thinks this is real?
This rare animal
is leaving its mark also in border states.
Rafael Licón will tell us about it.
People of the town
of San Javier
are still being haunted by El Chupacabras,
which has already killed
dozens of animals.
We advise everyone to stay indoors
during the night
and to keep a close eye
on children and pets.
Any information leading to its capture...
Why did you turn it off?
Because.
They were
talking about El Chupacabras.
No, mijo. Son mentiras. They're all lies.
Chupacabras doesn't exist.
I already told you that.
Do something else.
Find Memo. Go play with him.
It's too early to be watching TV.
I think
abuelo's up to something.
Last night, he snuck into the barn
and just sat there listening
to this music box.
It's sad.
I just keep hoping
he's going to get better, but...
Every time I come to visit,
he just gets worse.
My mom is probably right.
She thinks abuelo should move back
to Mexico City with us,
but his whole life is here in San Javier.
I don't think it's about that.
I think...
abuelo is hiding El Chupacabras.
You're too funny, primo.
I'm serious.
Abuelo's right.
El Chupacabras doesn't exist.
It's just a legend.
What are you?
You like that?
It's not food. Are you hungry?
Do you want to eat something?
Stay. Stay. Don't go.
- What's up?
- Nothing.
What's that for?
I'm hungry.
Oh, cousin.
It's okay.
I won't hurt you. It's all right.
Please don't hurt me.
It's all right. You can come out.
It's okay.
I don't know what you like.
So I brought you chorizo.
Here, try this.
No, not like that.
You're supposed to eat it. Eat.
Ugh!
No, it's for you.
Yes, you.
You're a funny little fella, aren't you?
Wait! Where are you going?
Come back! Don't go! Wait! Wait up!
Wait, wait, wait! No!
Please don't go! Please don't go!
So this is where you live?
What is this?
Ugh! Disgusting!
Oh... No, sorry, but I don't do mouse.
Well, don't be sad.
Okay, if you insist.
Okay, here it comes.
Here it goes.
Wow, that is really good. Thank you.
You got me, but there's no way
I'm eating that. Sorry.
It's just lightning.
Don't worry. You're safe inside.
It's okay, you're okay, don't worry.
You don't have to be alone anymore.
I'm gonna take care of you.
We can be together.
I'll be your family.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Did you hear that?
It could be a coyote. Come on.
Wait.
Shouldn't we tell abuelo?
Don't be a chicken, cuz.
Come on, it could be El Chupacabras.
They offer money to whomever
catches it, did you know?
Come on. Vámonos.
Wait.
I'm sure I heard something.
If we catch it, we'll be famous.
- We're going to be on the news.
- Go. Shoo.
With the reward,
we'll buy anything we want.
Shoo. Shoo.
- What is it?
- Nada.
There was a fly
buzzing by my head.
Vámonos.
Oh, my God!
It's okay.
He's my cousin. Calma.
- What is that?
- I think it's a chupacabras.
He doesn't
look like a monster.
I take that back.
Whatever it is, it's super cute.
Aww, good boy. Good boy.
What are you guys up to?
Don't scream. Don't scream.
He's harmless.
Are you crazy?
He's good, I promise.
Calma. Calma.
Calma. Good. Calma.
What is it?
- El Chupacabras!
- I can't believe this.
- Isn't he so cute?
- But we don't even know what it is.
It might be dangerous
or it could try to suck our blood.
Or what if he has rabies?
Or some weird disease or is full of...
- What should we name it?
- Are you nuts?
We're not keeping it
or giving it a name.
What about we call him Chupa?
You like that name, huh?
It's not a pet. It's wild animal.
It's decided. His name is Chupa.
You know "chupa" means sucker, right?
That's perfect
'cause he's my little sucker.
I don't know.
I think we should just put him outside.
No.
It has wings.
I'm sure it can fly back home.
He doesn't know how to.
- I can teach him!
- You can't fly.
Who says I can't?
He's just a baby.
We have to take care of him.
Alex is right.
You knew about this?
Hey!
Yes, but I don't want
anyone to know he's here.
You have to keep it a secret.
All right, Alex?
No one can know about this, kids. Okay?
That will be our little secret.
Some bad people out there
who want to take advantage of it.
People who want to hurt it.
You crashed?
I was driving home, mija.
It was dark.
And then suddenly this huge creature
came out of nowhere.
I couldn't stop.
What happened to it?
It ran off into the desert.
When I went back to get the car towed,
I heard this strange noise
from the bushes.
That's where I found this guy.
He must have gotten separated
from his family in the accident.
We have to find them.
We have to find his family.
I went back to look,
but I couldn't find him.
Chupa?
What are you doing?
Don't even think about it.
No. Chupa, no.
- Chupa, no!
- Hey!
No! Chupa! No!
No! Chupa!
Chupa! Leave him alone!
- Leave it alone!
- Chupa! Chupa!
Hey, Chupa!
Hey, come back! Come back!
That's right. Come on.
Chupa!
Good.
You're a funny little fella, aren't you?
That was crazy.
Poor Pepito.
- He almost got him.
- That would've been pretty bad.
Did you see
how fast that goat ran?
Hello, my friend.
Hello. How can I help you?
- Do you speak English?
- What do you want?
My associate and I
are with the US Government.
We're part of a program
that specializes in the research
of rare species for medical purposes.
There's only farm animals here.
I'm sorry, can't help you.
We found your bumper
by the side of the road.
You drive an '88 Beetle, don't you?
Our colleagues at the police department
have been very helpful.
They gave us your address.
What do you want?
Just a chance to have a look around.
Well, I don't think
that's going to be possible.
As a matter of fact,
I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
I know you saw it.
You know what a suplex is?
Some kind of rare species?
It's a beautiful lucha libre move.
You flip your opponent
and then he lands on his back... hard.
I was a master in my day,
so unless you get back in your car
and go back to where you came from,
I'll be happy to show you
what it looks like.
No need for a demonstration.
If you happen to see
anything strange or unusual,
don't hesitate to call.
I won't.
- Think he's lying?
- He knows something.
Is everything okay?
Yes, honey. It's all right.
He was here for Chupa,
wasn't he?
Yeah, but don't worry,
I won't let him hurt him.
Chupa?
Chupa! Where are you?
There you are. You can come out now.
That mean guy is gone.
You can come out now.
It's safe. I promise.
Okay! It's okay!
It's me. I'm not gonna hurt you.
This will cheer you up.
You like it, huh?
Pretty cool, huh?
My dad used to sing the same song to me
when I was little.
♪ Duerme ya que te cantaré ♪
♪ Y en tus sueños te buscaré ♪
♪ Donde estés, te acompañaré ♪
♪ Y a tu lado, yo ♪
♪ Siempre volaré ♪
He said it meant that
he would always be by my side.
I know that nothing I do
will ever bring my dad back.
But your family is still out there.
And I promise you, we will find them.
♪ Duerme ya que te cantaré ♪
♪ Y en tus sueños te buscaré ♪
What's up?
We were just listening to
abuelo's music box.
No time for that.
I need to teach him how to fly.
You want to teach Chupa
to do what?
First, spread your wings.
Like this!
Like that. Very good.
Then you take a step back,
and you fly!
It's your turn!
Come on. You need to learn
how to fly to escape the bad guys.
Go!
That's right! Now flap your wings!
Chupa!
Are you okay?
Well done! You almost made it.
This is my favorite fight, mijo.
He's my number one student,
El Perico Verde.
Check it out.
Wow, that was awesome!
Right? Yeah.
Wait. Wait, wait. Watch this next move.
Ouch! That must have hurt.
Yes. It's called a suplex.
That was my signature move.
Oh, but El Perico Verde...
He was way better at it than I ever was.
I don't know, abuelo.
You were pretty good.
It belonged to your father.
My dad was a luchador?
Sí, mijo. He was El Perico Verde.
He could have gone pro, you know?
Then he met your mother
and he understood that there are things
in life more important than lucha libre.
He was good. Oh, he was great.
He had all the skills
and he was strong and fast.
He could really, really fly.
What are you doing?
Don't you want to know about your dad
before you came along?
It hurts me too, you know that.
But we have to take it in,
we have to face it, feel it, all of it.
Alex, look at me.
Hey! What are you doing?
Talking to my grandson.
I don't feel like talking.
All right.
Then... let's fight.
What?
Yeah. You want this back?
You're gonna have to fight for it.
I'm not gonna fight you.
Well, then, you're not getting this back.
Really?
Pick it up, put it on,
make your dad proud.
Let's do this.
They'll fight two
out of three rounds with no time limit.
In this corner, the legend, the myth...
the one and only Relámpago Azul!
And in this corner, the surprise
of the night, El Perico Verde!
This is so stupid.
Shouldn't we be helping Chupa?
That man could come back at any moment.
I agree.
No, no, no. Not yet.
I first have to teach Alex
an important lesson.
Come on, son. Show me what you got.
Abuelo.
Fight!
- This is stupid.
- Come on!
You're sad, son. That's normal.
He has him by the neck!
You're hurt.
I'm not hurt.
I just really want to be left alone.
No. That's okay.
Let it out. Let it out. All right?
Channel those emotions.
Take it all out on me. Come on.
I don't want to fight you.
He throws him to the ground!
Leave him alone.
I've been watching you, Alex.
Get off me!
One...
Every time
your dad gets brought up,
you retreat and hide
in that stupid game of yours.
You're choking me!
Two...
Face your pain,
face your fears and your sorrow.
You have to feel the pain of the sadness.
And three!
Azul!
- Abuelo!
- Are you okay?
Can you get up?
I'm so sorry, abuelo.
I didn't mean to push you.
I don't know what got into me.
I'm really sorry.
Hey, kids, come on.
We have to let him rest. Vámonos.
You must be Alex.
Chava told me about you.
He was very excited you were coming.
You, uh... You live in Cincinnati, right?
Kansas City.
You know, I went to school in Columbus.
It is very beautiful up there.
Is abuelo gonna be all right?
It's just a bump.
I gave him some medicine for the pain,
but he was very disoriented.
So how's his memory been?
It's perfect.
Well, he did go missing yesterday.
He likes to get exercise,
he just went for a walk.
You know, your abuelo is a strong man,
but his condition is just gonna get worse.
His farm is a lot for one man to care for.
He can do it.
Let's hope so.
What was that?
It was a cow.
That didn't sound like a cow.
It was a sick cow.
A very sick cow.
He's okay.
That's why I never wanted
to be a veterinarian.
Thank you so much.
Okay, bueno. Take care of your abuelito.
Sí.
You need me, you call me.
Okay. Gracias.
Be good.
- Adiós.
Adiós.
It's Chupa.
Something's wrong.
No, no! Stop! Chupa!
Stay back! It's dangerous.
He's not dangerous! Please, put that down!
Get out of the way!
You don't know what you're dealing with!
No! Chupa, no! No!
- Chupa!
- Chupa! No!
It's okay! It'll calm down!
No!
There he goes.
He's gonna conk out.
- Let it take effect.
- No!
Okay. Stay back!
- Lo mataste!
- How could you?
Relax. It's a mild sedative,
it's gonna be fine.
Okay. I can't believe it.
It's beautiful.
Okay. Calm down. Calm down.
It's gonna be okay. Calm down.
No!
Chupa!
It's okay.
We're gonna get him back.
Gotcha.
Abuelo!
Abuelo, wake up!
- Qué pasa?
- We have to go! Now!
Beto, mijo.
No, no, no, I'm not Beto.
Beto's my dad. I'm Alex.
- Remember? Alex!
- What Alex? What Alex?
No time to explain.
Just put your shoes on.
No, I'm not going anywhere.
This is my house.
Por favor, abuelo. We have to save Chupa!
Who's Chupa?
Chupa! The creature you found
on the side of the road. Remember Chupa?
- Abuelo, remember. He's my friend. Please!
- No. Please. Slow down, please.
I'm not feeling good.
I'm not good, please.
I just wanna sleep.
- Easy does it. There you go.
- Hey! What are you doing?
Where are you taking him?
Don't worry about it. He's gonna be fine.
Come on, abuelo.
We gotta go. We gotta hurry.
You sure about this?
I told you, your enemy is on the loose.
El Chakal?
Sí. Sí. El Chakal. Come on.
- Let's go!
- Yeah, let's go stop him.
Oh, hold on.
- What now?
- I just have to grab this one.
We don't even need that.
- Come on, abuelo. We really have to go!
- All right.
- Come on, hurry up. El Chakal is waiting.
- I'm coming.
Okay. Just give me one second,
pequeño amigo.
A luchador never goes anywhere
without his cape.
Abuelo, come on.
- Hey!
- I've had it with all of you!
These are my grandchildren!
Who are you?
I'm Quinn.
What the heck are you?
This is my house.
What are you doing in my home?
It's El Chakal.
El Chakal? Are you sure?
After so many years,
we finally meet again.
How dare you come into my house!
Whoa Hey! Take it easy!
Yes! Let's go!
You can do it!
Whoa, whoa!
Azul!
Abuelo! Vámonos!
Hurry up!
Vamos. Hurry up.
Come on, abuelo! Come on.
Vámonos. Vámonos. Hurry up!
Oh, come on, come on!
Oh, no, no, no!
- Hurry up! He's coming!
- I'm trying.
El Chakal?
- No. He's coming, let's go!
- It's stuck!
- Move!
- Hurry up!
Hurry up! Move!
Come on! Hurry up!
- Come on!
- Stop the car! Come on, open up!
- Don't let him in.
- Stop!
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Stop! Whoa, whoa!
- Hey! Hey, stop! Stop the car!
- No!
Azul!
- Yeah! Let's go!
- Yeah!
Yeah!
Man! That was awesome back there, abuelo.
Nice kick.
But where are we going?
It's okay.
We're gonna help Chupa.
Chupa?
- Here.
- Whoa!
That's Chupa.
We're gonna take him home,
back to his family.
Chupa.
What kept you?
They got away! Come on! Come on!
Is this where the accident happened?
I think so. Yeah.
Come on, abuelo, try to remember. Try.
I'm trying. I'm trying.
Which way did the creature come from?
Uh... There? There?
- Which way did it go?
- I...
I'm not sure.
I'm so sorry.
I can't remember.
It's okay, abuelo.
Guys? Chupa is acting weird.
Chupa? Chupa, what's the matter?
Are you okay?
It's okay, boy. Chupa? Chupa, wait!
- Wait, where are you going?
- Chupa!
- Alex! Hey! Alex!
- Alex!
You won't reach him!
- Hijo!
- Chupa!
- Alex!
- Stop!
Come on, come on, you little stinks.
Where are you?
There it is, pull over!
Got it.
See that?
Circle the area.
I'm going to check the truck!
Copy that!
Right, I'll head west, you head east.
Copy that.
We'll take east.
Chupa! Come back!
Chupa! Chupa!
Where are you going? Don't go!
Alex! Wait for us!
- Come back!
- Cousin!
Alex! Wait up, mijo!
Wait! Chupa, wait!
What got into you?
I don't...
Is that... your family?
That's amazing.
I get it.
You gotta go now.
I'm gonna miss you, buddy.
I'm really glad you found your family.
Bye! Be safe!
Shoo! Shoo!
Get away! Shoo! Go!
Please, leave me alone.
- Alex!
- Abuelo! Help!
Azul!
Leave my grandson alone!
- Alex!
- We'll help you!
Just stay there!
Watch out!
Stay behind me.
- Careful, grandpa.
- Get out of here!
Leave! Go away!
Watch out!
Go away!
Mijo! Hang in there!
Hang in there!
Come on, wait.
Now, easy. We got this, okay?
Let's get you off this pipe.
- I'm scared, abuelo. I can't.
- Now, very easy.
Get up and walk towards me. Okay?
Good. That's it.
Go, Alex!
No. Don't look down.
Alex! Look at me!
- Quickly!
- Don't look down.
Alex!
Abuelo!
- Hold on, son! I'm coming!
- Abuelo!
- Help!
- Please, God, no!
Hang on!
Help! Help! Help!
Help! Help me, please! Help!
- Help!
- Come on, Alex!
Hey! Hang in there!
Help!
I can't hold on.
Abuelo!
Look! Chupa!
There he is!
Help!
Come on, Chupa, come on.
Help! Help!
You came back!
Hurry! Hurry!
- No!
- Hold on! Hold on!
- Don't let go!
Chupa, you can do it!
Please, no.
- No!
- No, no, no!
No!
You did it! You did it!
You're flying! You're flying!
He can fly!
- Alex!
- I can't believe it.
Well done, Chupa!
Very good, Chupa. Very good.
Careful. Careful not to let him go,
please. Careful.
Easy! Don't let go of him.
I got you, mijo. Leave him here.
Don't let him fall. Oh, my son.
Thank you! Oh, lord!
Mijo! You almost gave me a heart attack.
That was pretty scary.
- I'm proud of you.
- I'm glad you're okay.
You did it, Chupa!
Just like I taught you.
Thanks for coming back.
You saved my life.
- What happened? Chupa?
- Chupa? Chupa? Chupa?
- Stay back! Stay back!
- Don't you! What did you do to him?
Stay back! All of you!
Don't do anything stupid, old man!
- It's okay.
- What did you do?
- No! Chupa!
- No, no, no.
Back off! This thing will zap you
clear across the canyon!
- Let him go!
- You should be ashamed!
Listen to me, I've had it
up to here with all of you.
He belongs with his family!
- You have to let him go.
- Stop being so dramatic, kid.
- It's okay.
- Go home. Get a dog.
- It's okay. Mijo...
- Chupa! Chupa! Chupa!
- Let him go. It's all right. No.
- Chupa! No, no!
- It's okay.
- No, no!
Now that I got you,
I'm not letting you out of my sight.
You're riding shotgun, little guy.
- Alex!
- Come on! We have to help!
There's nothing we can do!
No!
No! Wait, wait, wait! Stop, stop!
We have to do something!
No. There's nothing we can do, son.
I'm sorry, Alex. We tried.
I finally got it. Let's meet back at base.
- Roger. Congrats, Quinn.
- Take you in.
We're going to show 'em
I was right all along.
What's gonna happen to him?
No one knows, mijo.
I'm sorry, primo.
Look! Over there!
Wow.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Come on!
Come on! Come on!
Yeah! That's right! Yeah!
- Yeah!
- I can't believe it!
Yeah!
Take it easy! Take it easy!
Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Just relax!
This is just a... huge misunderstanding!
I don't want to hurt him.
Hey! Easy!
You don't want to be zapped!
You just gotta back off!
I said back off!
Okay. All right. That's good.
We can work this out.
Nice and easy.
Oh!
All right. Put him down.
- Easy. Put him down.
- Okay! He's down!
There you go. Go, Chupa, go!
All right, get off! You can let me go!
It's time you learn
about the beauty of the suplex.
- That's right, Grandpa!
- Yeah!
Azul!
Vamos!
How did he do it?
That's right, Grandpa!
It's time for you to go now.
I'm gonna miss you.
Just remember, that wherever you are,
I will always be by your side.
Be safe.
Are you sad?
No, not really.
He found his family. And I found mine.
Wanna go get some tacos?
What?
Do you feel like having more sesos?
Nah, I think I'll stick to barbacoa.
I'm sad you're leaving.
Me too.
But I'll come back, I promise.
You better.
I made you this tape
with some cool Mexican bands.
That way you can practice your Spanish.
Thanks. I'll check it out
when I get back home.
Take this, so you can
listen to it on the plane.
Are you sure?
I'm glad you came, primo.
Me too.
We're gonna miss you, Alex.
Where's Memo?
Where's he now? Memo!
Come say goodbye to your cousin,
he's leaving!
- Did you see him?
- No.
- Memo?
- Memo!
Never mind. Let's go.
I'll make sure he calls you when you land.
Cowabunga!
Defend yourself, Alex.
Give up, cousin.
No!
You give up!
Very good, Alex.
That's right. Stay on top.
- Azul!
- Yeah!
Can't wait to tell my mom
all about this trip.
I had a lot of fun.
I loved Mexico.
Whoa!
- Muy bien!
- Thanks.
Don't stop
talking in Spanish, okay?
Don't worry.
I'll practice with my mom.
That's good.
Always be proud of who you are.
- Don't let anyone tell you otherwise.
- I won't.
And if anyone tries to mess with me,
well, I know a few lucha libre moves.
That's right.
My dad was right.
This place... really is magical.
Buen día. Por acá.
Gracias, señorita.
- De nada.
- Bueno, mijo.
Well, take care, abuelo.
Don't go wandering off
or anything like that.
I'll try my best.
But your primos will take good care of me.
Are you sad about leaving San Javier?
Not really.
It's always good to be with family.
Mexico City is a big city,
I'm afraid I might get lost in it.
If you get lost,
your family will find you.
You're right.
Listen, mijo.
I'm going to ask you a big favor
and I keep forgetting things,
my brain is not what it used to be.
So I'm counting on you to remember
everything that happened here.
Trust me, I'll never forget.
Gracias, mijo.
Safe travels.
- Give my love to your mom.
- Okay.
Wait! Wait!
Don't close the doors. Hold on.
Sorry, I forgot to give you something.
Oh. Are you sure?
I want you to have it.
I don't need it anymore.
Love you, son.
I love you, Grandpa.
I'm gonna miss you.
I'll miss you too, mijo.
Be good, all right? Take care.
- Azul!
- Adiós, abuelo.
- Adiós, mijo.
Chupa!
♪ Como el ave deja su nido ♪
♪ Y la Oruga aprende a volar ♪
♪ Esta vida te dará alas ♪
♪ Y muy lejos ♪
♪ Te iras ♪
♪ Si algún día te sientes triste ♪
♪ Y ese día quieres llorar ♪
♪ Simplemente cierra los ojos ♪
♪ Y me verás ♪
♪ Duerme ya que te cantare ♪
♪ Y en tus sueños te buscare ♪
♪ Donde estés te acompañare ♪
♪ Y a tu lado yo ♪
♪ Siempre volare ♪
♪ Como la hembra defiende a su cría ♪
♪ Del coyote, el avestruz, y el chaval ♪
♪ Con mi vida protejo la tuya ♪
♪ De cualquier tempestad ♪
♪ Si en el aire te sientes triste ♪
♪ Y ese día quieres llorar ♪
♪ Simplemente cierra los ojos ♪
♪ Y me veras ♪
♪ Duerme ya que te cantare ♪
♪ Y en tus sueños te buscare ♪
♪ Donde estés te acompañare ♪
♪ Y a tu lado yo ♪
♪ Siempre volare ♪
♪ Del más allá se escucha un rugido ♪
♪ Y la tierra quiere temblar ♪
♪ No temas más que estoy a tu lado ♪
♪ Y en mis brazos duermes ya ♪
♪ Si el vacío se vuelve triste ♪
♪ Y en la noche quieres llorar ♪
♪ Simplemente cierra los ojos ♪
♪ Y me verás ♪
♪ Duerme ya que te cantare ♪
♪ Y en tus sueños te buscare ♪
♪ Donde estés te acompañare ♪
♪ Y a tu lado yo ♪
♪ Siempre estoy ♪
♪ Duerme ya que te cantare ♪
♪ Y en tus sueños te buscare ♪
♪ Donde estés te acompañare ♪
♪ Y a tu lado yo ♪
♪ Siempre volare ♪